The brain is an amazing and complex organ.
الدماغ هو عضو معقد ومدهش .
about the properties about how the brain works
عن خصائص وكيفية عمل الدماغ
because we don't teach neuroscience in schools.
لأننا لا ندرس علم الأعصاب في المدارس .
And one of the reasons why is that the equipment
ومن أهم الأسباب أيضاً أن المعدات
is so complex and so expensive
معقدة وباهظة الثمن جداً
that it's really only done at major universities and large institutions.
ولذلك لا تستخدم هذه المعدات إلا في الجامعات الرئيسية والمعاهد الكبيرة .
And so in order to be able to access the brain,
وهكذا حتى نتمكن من الوصول إلى الدماغ ،
you really need to dedicate your life
فأنت حقاً بحاجة إلى أن تكرس حياتك
and spend six and a half years as a graduate student
وقضاء ست سنوات ونصف كطالب دراسات عليا
just to become a neuroscientist to get access to these tools.
فقط لتصبح متخصصا في الأعصاب ويتاح لك استخدام هذه الأدوات.
And that's a shame because one out of five of us,
وهذا شيء مخجل لأن 1 من كل 5 منا ،
that's 20 percent of the entire world, will have a neurological disorder.
وهذا ما يشكل نسبة 20٪ من العالم كله، سيكون لديهم اضطراب عصبي .
And there are zero cures for these diseases.
ولا توجد أي علاجات لهذه الأمراض .
And so it seems that what we should be doing
وهكذا يبدو أن ما يجب ان نفعله
is reaching back earlier in the eduction process
هو الوصول بوقت باكر إلى عملية الإستنباط
and teaching students about neuroscience so that in the future,
وتعليم الطلاب عن علم الأعصاب في المستقبل ،
they may be thinking about possibly becoming a brain scientist.
فربما يفكرون بأن يصبحوا علماء في الأعصاب .
decided that what if we took this complex equipment that we have
قلنا لبعضنا ماذا لو أخذنا هذه المعدات التي بحوزتنا
for studying the brain and made it simple enough and affordable enough
واستخدمناها لدراسة الدماغ وجعلناها متاحة بأسعار معقولة بما فيه الكفاية
that anyone that you know, an amateur or a high school student,
بحيث أن أي شخص ،سواءاً كان من الهواة أو أحد طلاب المرحلة الثانوية ،
could learn and actually participate in the discovery of neuroscience.
يمكن أن يتعلم ويشارك في الواقع في اكتشاف علم الأعصاب.
And so we did just that.
وهذا ما قمنا به .
A few years ago, we started a company called Backyard Brains
وقبل بضع سنوات، بدأنا شركة تدعى "باكيارد برينز"
and we make DIY neuroscience equipment and I brought some here tonight,
وقمنا بعمل معدات الأعصاب التي أحضرت جزءاً منها هنا ،
and I want to do some demonstrations.
وأريد أن أقوم ببعض العروض لكم .
You guys want to see some?
أيها الرفاق هل تودون رؤية بعض من هذه العروض ؟
So I need a volunteer.
إذاً أنا بحاجة لمتطوع .
So right before -- what is your name? (Applause)
حسناً قبل كل شيء --ما هو اسمك ؟ (تصفيق )
Sam Kelly: Sam.
سام كيلي: سام.
Greg Gage: All right, Sam, I'm going to record from your brain.
جريج غيج :حسناً ، سأقوم بالتسجيل من دماغك .
Have you had this before?
هل قمت بهذه التجربة من قبل ؟
SK: No.
سام : لا .
GG: I need you to stick out your arm for science,
جريج غيج :أريد منك الآن بأن تقومي بمد يدك لهذه التجربة ،
roll up your sleeve a bit,
قومي بكف اًكمام قميصك قليلاً ،
So what I'm going to do, I'm putting electrodes on your arm,
ما سأقوم بفعله الآن هو وضع الأقطاب الكهربائية على ذراعك ،
and you're probably wondering,
وعلى الأغلب أنت تستغربين ،
I just said I'm going to record from your brain, what am I doing with your arm?
لأنني قلت للتو بأنني سأسجل من دماغك فماذا سأفعل بيدك ؟
Well, you have about 80 billion neurons inside your brain right now.
حسناً ،لديك ما يقارب من ال 80 مليار خلية عصبية في دماغك الآن .
They're sending electrical messages back and forth, and chemical messages.
إنهم يرسلون رسائل الكترونية وكيمائية ذهاباً وإياباً .
But some of your neurons right here in your motor cortex
ولكن بعض خلاياك العصبية هنا في القشرة الحركية الخاصة بك
are going to send messages down when you move your arm like this.
ستقوم بإرسال رسائل للأسفل عندما تقوم بتحريك يدك هكذا .
They're going to go down across your corpus callosum,
ستنزل هذه الرسائل للأسفل عن طريق جزء من دماغك ،
down onto your spinal cord to your lower motor neuron
تنزل عبر نخاعك الشوكي إلى الخلايا العصبية الحركية الخاصة بك
out to your muscles here,
إلى عضلاتك هنا،
and that electrical discharge is going to be picked up
وهذا التفريغ الكهربائي سيتم التقاطه
by these electrodes right here
من خلال هذه الأقطاب هنا
and we're going to be able to listen
وسنكون قادرين على سماع ذلك
to exactly what your brain is going to be doing.
بشكل مماثل لما يقوم به دماغك الآن .
So I'm going to turn this on for a second.
لذا سأقوم بتشغيل هذا لعدة ثواني .
Have you ever heard what your brain sounds like?
هل سبق لك أن سمعت صوت دماغك ؟
SK: No.
سام : لا
GG: Let's try it out. So go ahead and squeeze your hand.
جريج غيج :حسناً ،دعونا نحاول ذلك . إبدئي بذلك وقومي بالضغط على يدك .
(Rumbling)
(صرير)
So what you're listening to,
ما كنت تستمعين له ،
so this is your motor units happening right here.
هو وحداتك الحركية التي تحدث الآن .
Let's take a look at it as well.
دعونا نلقي نظرة علىها كذلك.
So I'm going to stand over here,
لذلك أنا سأقف هنا،
and I'm going to open up our app here.
وسأقوم بفتح هذا التطبيق هنا .
So now I want you to squeeze.
الآن أريد منك أن تضغطي على يدك .
(Rumbling)
(صرير )
So right here, these are the motor units that are happening
إذاً هنا ،هذه هيا وحداتك الحركية التي تحدث الآن
from her spinal cord out to her muscle right here,
من نخاعها الشوكي إلى عضلاتها هنا ،
and as she's doing it,
كما تفعلها الآن ،
you're seeing the electrical activity that's happening here.
أنتم تشاهدون النشاطات الكهربائية التي تحدث هنا .
You can even click here and try to see one of them.
يمكنكم حتى النقر هنا ومحاولة مشاهدة إحدى هذه النشاطات .
So keep doing it really hard.
وبالتالي الحفاظ على فعل ذلك من الصعب حقا.
So now we've paused
الآن توقفنا
on one motor action potential that's happening right now inside of your brain.
على واحدة من التغيرات الحركية التي تحدث داخل دماغك الآن .
Do you guys want to see some more?
هل تريدون يا رفاق مشهدة المزيد ؟
(Applause)
(تصفيق )
That's interesting, but let's get it better.
هذا ممتع ولكن دعونا نجعله أكثر متعة .
I need one more volunteer.
أريد متطوعاً آخر .
What is your name, sir?
ما اسمك سيدي ؟
You're going to stand right here.
ستقوم بالوقوف هنا .
So when you're moving your arm like this,
وعندما تقوم بتحريك يدك هكذا ،
your brain is sending a signal down to your muscles right here.
سيقوم دماغك بإرسال إشارة لعضلاتك في الأسفل هنا .
I want you to move your arm as well.
أريدك أنت أيضاً أن تقوم بتحريك يدك .
So your brain is going to send a signal down to your muscles.
حتى يقوم دماغك بإرسال إشارة لعضلاتك في الأسفل هنا .
And so it turns out that there is a nerve that's right here
يتضح لنا أن هناك عصب هنا
that runs up here that innervates these three fingers,
التي تعمل هنا وتقوم بتزويد هذه الأصابع الثلاثة بالأعصاب ،
and it's close enough to the skin that we might be able
والتي هي قريبة بما فيه الكفاية من الجلد الذي سنكون قادرين على
to stimulate that so that what we can do
أن نحفزه و ما نستطيع القيام به
is copy your brain signals going out to your hand
هو أن نقوم بنسخ إشارات الدماغ المرتبطة بيدك
and inject it into your hand,
وحقنها وبرمجتها بيدك ،
so that your hand will move when your brain tells your hand to move.
وهكذا فإن يدك ستتحرك عندما يخبر دماغك يدك بالتحرك .
So in a sense, she will take away your free will
بمعنى أنها تسلبك الشعور
and you will no longer have any control over this hand.
ولن يعود لديك أي سيطرة على يدك .
You with me?
هل انتم جاهزون ؟
So I just need to hook you up.
اذاّ أنا سأقوم بربطكم ببعض .
(Laughter)
(ضحك )
So I'm going to find your ulnar nerve,
سأقوم بالبحث عن عصبك الزندي ،
which is probably right around here.
الذي هو على الأغلب هنا .
when you come up.
عندما جئتم هنا .
Okay, so Sam, I want you to squeeze your hand again.
حسناً ،سام ، أريد منك أن تقومي بالضغط على يدك وتحريكها مرة أخرى .
Do it again. Perfect.
حركيها مرة أخرى.ممتاز.
So now I'm going to hook you up over here so that you get the --
الآن سأقوم بربطكم مع بعضكم البعض حتى يتسنى لكم الحصول على--
It's going to feel a little bit weird at first,
ستشعر شعور غريب في البداية ،
this is going to feel like a -- (Laughter)
شعور كما لو أنه -- (ضحك )
You know, when you lose your free will, and someone else becomes your agent,
كما تعلمون ،عندما تفقد السيطرة على أحد أعضائك ويقوم شخص آخر بالشعور بهذه العضو،
it does feel a bit strange.
فإنه شعور غريب نوعاً ما .
Now I want you to relax your hand.
الآن أريد منكم أن ترخي يديك .
Sam, you're with me?
سام، أنت معي؟
So you're going to squeeze.
إذاً ستقومين بالضغط على يدك .
I'm not going to turn it on yet, so go ahead and give it a squeeze.
لن أقوم بتشغيلها الآن ،لذا قم بالضغط .
So now, are you ready, Miguel?
هل أنت جاهز الآن ميغل ؟
MG: Ready as I'll ever be.
ميغل :جاهز ككل مرة .
GG: I've turned it on, so go ahead and turn your hand.
جريج غيج :حسناً ،سأشغل الجهاز والآن قومي بتحريك يدك .
Do you feel that a little bit? MG: Nope.
هل تشعر بيدك قليلاً ؟ ميغل : لا .
GG: Okay, do it again? MG: A little bit.
جريج عنج :حسناً ،حركها مرة أخرى ؟ ميغل :قليلاً .
GG: A little bit? (Laughter)
جريج غيج :قليلاً ؟ (ضحك )
So relax.
الآن إهدأ .
So hit it again.
حركيها مرة أخرى .
(Laughter)
(ضحك )
Oh, perfect, perfect.
جميل ،جميل .
So relax, do it again.
اهدأ ،حركيها مرة أخرى.
All right, so right now,
حسناً ،الآن ،
your brain is controlling your arm and it's also controlling his arm,
دماغك يسيطرعلى ذراعك ويسيطر على ذراعه أيضاً ،
so go ahead and just do it one more time.
قومي بذلك مرة أخرى .
All right, so it's perfect. (Laughter)
حسناً ،جميل (ضحك )
So now, what would happen if I took over my control of your hand?
الآن ،ما الذي سيحصل لو قمت بإزالة السيطرة عن يدك ؟
And so, just relax your hand.
لذا ،قومي بإرخاء يديك .
What happens?
ما الذي حصل ؟
Ah, nothing.
اها ، لاشيء .
Why not?
لماذا ؟
Because the brain has to do it.
لأن الدماغ سيقوم بذلك .
So you do it again.
يمكنك أن تفعل ذلك مرة أخرى.
All right, that's perfect.
حسناً ،هذا جميل .
Thank you guys for being such a good sport.
شكرأ لكم يا رفاق لكونكم جزء من هذه الرياضة.
This is what's happening all across the world --
وهذا هو ما يحدث في جميع أنحاء العالم -
electrophysiology!
الفيزيولوجيا الكهربية !
We're going to bring on the neuro-revolution.
ونحن في طريقنا لتحقيق الثورة العصبية.
Thank you.
شكراً
(Applause)
(تصفيق )